In 2018, a scandal between Facebook and Cambridge Analytica
revealed that personal data from millions of users
was used without their consent.
This scandal made the term #deletefacebook very popular in social media
and many people encouraged each other to delete their Facebook account.
However, if you take a look at the average daily users,
then you can only barely see a dent at the time of the scandal.
So why didn't everyone delete their Facebook account?
Well that's because LEAVING FACEBOOK IS A LUXURY.
Leaving Facebook not only means that you leave the service,
it also means you leave a lot of friends behind.
And for many people, this includes family members, friends, organisations that they're part of etc.
Those people need interoperability.
Interoperability means that different apps can communicate with each other.
Take Element for example, which can communicate with WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, Discord and many more,
and you can even combine people from different apps in one group chat.
This gets rid of the network effect: you no longer need to care what platform your friends are using.
Support interoperability by reading more on the Digital Justice website.